Guide to the Robert Colodny Papers ALBA.211
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- Series I: General Files
  - VALB: The Volunteer correspondence and materials, 1975-1995 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - VALB: Wachtel, Marion (Merriman), 1970-1992 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Vidal, Gore, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Vidali, Vittorio (Carlos): Correspondence, 1965-1994 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Vidali, Vittorio (Carlos): Diary(Colodny introduction), undated, 1982 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Vietnam: Correspondence with Colodny on Peace Movement, 1965-1968 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Vietnam: Correspondence with servicemen, 1965, 1971 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Vietnam: Peace Movement: Articles, pamphlets, flyers, 1964-1969 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Vietnam: Peace Movement: Teach-ins, 1961-1967 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Vietnam: Political Correspondence with Dorothy Colodny, 1966-1967 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Warped Vision, by Margaret George (Colodny foreword), 1965 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - World War II: "Adakian" writings, undated (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - World War II: Alaska/Aleutian Theater - Dashiell Hammett, 1943, 1967-1993 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - World War II: Alaska/Aleutian Theater - General, undated, 1959, 1982-1991 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - World War II: Articles about, undated (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - World War II: "Sergeant Robert Colodny 'On the Air'" (article), c.1943 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - World War II: "World in Review" - WXLB Radio Scripts, 1945 (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Writings: Book review (by Colodny): Bolloten-Correspondence, 1979-1980 (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - Writings: Book reviews (by Colodny), undated, 1964-1992 (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - Writings: Book reviews (by Colodny): Clippings scrapbook, 1948-1951 (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - Writings: Book reviews (by Colodny): Spanish Civil War, 1961-1996 (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - Writings: Book reviews (of Colodny work):, 1958, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - Writings: Correspondence regarding, 1963-1996 (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - Writings: General: Published, undated, 1953-1958, 1980 (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - Writings: General: Typescripts, undated, 1968-1984 (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - Writings: Poetry (by Colodny and others), undated, 1968-1972 (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - Writings: Promotion of, 1995 (Box 5, Folder 37)
  - Writings: Spain, the Glory, and the Tragedy: Correspondence and Reviews, 1965-1975 (Box 5, Folder 38)
  - Writings: Spain, the Glory, and the Tragedy(Typescript), undated (Box 5, Folder 39)
  - Writings: Spain and Vietnam, 1967-1970 (Box 5, Folder 40)
  - Writings: on Spanish Civil War, undated (Box 5, Folder 41)
  - Writings: Words for Peace(Typescript), 1983 (Box 5, Folder 42)
  - Young, Stephen M. (U.S. Senate), 1960 (Box 5, Folder 43)
- Series II: Oversize Materials, Scrapbook, Audio- and Videotapes.
  - Hollywood Anti-Nazi League for the Defense of American Democracy, undated (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - World War II: The Adakian and other writings, 1944-1945 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - World War II: Radio programs: July 4th and V-J Day, 1945 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Writings: Drafts written on notepads, undated (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Audiotape (1, Reel-to-Reel): Teach-in (Vietnam War era), ca.1965-1975 (Box 6)
  - Videotapes (2): "Robert Colodny: Living His/Story" and "Robert Colodny, July 24, 1986" (Use DVD reference copies in same box), undated (Box 6)
    Conditions Governing Access
    Access copies for some materials are available by appointment for reading room viewing and listening only. Please contact the Tamiment Library & Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives for more information and to schedule an appointment, tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu or 212-998-2630.
  - Scrapbook: Colodny Case (University of Pittsburgh), 1960-1962, 1967 (Box 6)